One symbol of the current phase of the
conflict has become the Kbar Shakhan
missile, which has achieved some
successes in strikes against American
targets across [music] the region. The
Kbar Shakhan has a range of at least
1,450
km and unlike many other Iranian
designs, does not require a lengthy
launch procedure. It uses solid fuel and
therefore does not need to be fueled
before launch. This allows it to be
fired quickly from a mobile launcher,
making it extremely [music] difficult to
detect. The missile is even more
dangerous because some variants are
capable of maneuvering during the
terminal phase of the flight. Iran
combines Kbaran missiles with cheap
drones and older, less sophisticated
rockets, allowing it to overwhelm US air
defenses more effectively. One example
of a successful attack involving the
Kbar Shakhan was the strike on Mouafak
air base in Jordan where three American
soldiers were killed.